CARL MASTNY





SUMMARY

I fell in love with coding in college. Seeing the fruit of your labor as you find solutions to programming problems has been a satisfying experience. Although my first hello world program may have taken me a couple hours to figure out, I've come a long way, learning useful skills in Java and C++. I can't wait to use my skills in a professional setting.



SKILLS

- Microsoft Office Suite
- Java
- C++

- HTML/CSS/JavaScript
- Customer Service
- 60 WPM

- Problem Solver
- Fast Learner
- Team Player



EDUCATION

Prairie State College / Chicago Heights II. / A.A.S. IT Programming

Computer Support Technician (Certificate) / Web Development Technician (Certificate)

Graduated with a 4.0 GPA. I took classes in Java, C++, and programming logic. Through coursework I:

- Learned object-oriented design principles
- Used and implemented data structures (linked and doubly linked lists, array lists, queues, binary trees, etc.)
- Implemented and animated sorting algorithms
- Generated statistical reports based on comma separated value text files



EXPERIENCE

Training Coordinator / Holland LP / March 2018 - August 2019

- Created and managed travel plans on a weekly basis for groups of up to 15 new hires at one time, i.e. flights, hotels, Uber, meals
- Developed effective solutions to managing PPE inventory, flight information, and hotel confirmation numbers using Microsoft Excel's data features
- Maintained 15 training laptops by troubleshooting issues, defragging disks, and personalizing displays

Administrative Assistant / Hydra Stop / June 2017 - August 2017

- Implemented Excel's data features to document financial and inventory data
- Navigated database software to retrieve pertinent information
- Configured backup drives on a weekly basis to ensure data preservation

Tire Technician / Discount Tire / December 2019 – Present

- Contribute to a fast-paced team workflow to effectively balance and rotate tires for up to 50 vehicles a day
- Troubleshoot to decipher air leak points, and create solutions by implementing proper patchwork technique
- Administer proper control protocol when using heavy hydraulic machinery to create a safe and efficient work environment